Philip Whitty

Address: Nuke, Campile, New Ross, Co.Wexford

Tel: 085 - 824 6400

Email: philipwhitty92@yahoo.ie
Driver's Licence: Full Drivers Licence

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am currently pursuing a software development program with Code Institute, scheduled to conclude in December 2023. Motivated, enthusiastic, individual with experience and exposure. Excels whilst working in a challenging and demanding fast paced environments who is motivated by deadlines, targets and delivery schedules, continually adhering to health and safety regulations and procedures. Highly organised with excellent adaptability skills, who enjoys practical learning and takes pride in continually reaching the required work standards

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

Nuke Construction Ltd 2021-2022

Coded Pipe Welder - Self Employed

Areas of responsibility:

- Independently receiving job contracts
- Carrying out Tig Welding process in Regeneron Pharmaceutical Plant
- Pipe Fitting and Welding procedures carried out in Sincon Engineerings workshop
- Ensuring all welds were up to standard with the specifications of weld x-rays
- Operation of Machinery including MEWP's and Forklifts
- Complied with Health and Safety regulations, procedures, and guidelines

Mcm Engineering 2016-2021

Coded Pipe Welder

Areas of responsibility:

- Working on Google Database Centres in the Netherlands, Denmark and Finland
- Carrying out Tig Welding process on these projects
- Pipe Fitting and Welding procedures carried out in Mcms workshop Bagnelstown
- Ensuring all welds were up to standard with the specifications of weld x-rays
- Operation of Machinery including MEWP's and Forklifts
- Strict adherence to Health and Safety regulations, procedures and guidelines

Radley Engineering 2014 – 2015

General Operative

Areas of responsibility:

- Working on a variety of projects including Glanbia Project in Killkenny and Regeneron Pharmaceutical Plant in Limerick for Radley Engineering
- Responsible for working with a variety of steel and pipework
- Carrying out carbon/ stainless bracket fabrication, in line with specifications
- Accountable for cutting and utilising gas cutting tools and drilling equipment
- MIG welding brackets in the Radley workshop on site
- Set up welding plants for other welders
- Operating machinery such as MEWPs
- Ensuring all work is carried out in line with all relevant work instructions, procedures and policies
- Strict adherence to Health and Safety regulations, procedures and guidelines
- Carried out additional requested duties as needed

Philip Whitty CV Page 1 of 2

Centra Ramsgrange

Shop Assistant 2013

Areas of responsibility:

- Responsible for various tasks including customer service, stocking shelves, and cashier duties
- Handled cash transactions accurately and efficiently
- Assisted in maintaining cleanliness and organisation of the store
- Provided support in other areas of the store as needed

EDUCATIONAL EXPERIENCE & QUALIFICATIONS

2022 Code Institute

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Course Content:

HTML/CSS Essentials
JavaScript Essentials

Python Essentials

GitHub

UX Essentials

Design Thinking

Advanced JavaScript
APIs and Frameworks

Agile Development

Agrie Develop

Bootstrap
Testing Code

2016 Coded Pipe Welding Programme

CETB (Cork Education & Training Board) in conjunction with Impact Training

Certification:

ASME IX and EN ISO 9606-1 and EN ISO 9606-2 Standards

Carbon Steel Pipe 6" E 6011 Root, E6013 Fill and Cap

Carbon Steel Pipe 6" PZ 6500 T.I.G Root, E7018 Fill and Cap

Carbon Steel Pipe 3" PZ 6500 T.I.G. Complete Multi Run Sequence

Stainless Steel Pipe 2" T.I.G. 316, One Run Sequence

Stainless Steel Pipe 3" Complete

Other Modules: Safe Pass, Manual Handling, Abrasive Wheels, Confined Spaces

2015 Intermediate Welding Programme

Machine Tools (Welding)

Manual Metal Arc Welding Intermediate

Mig Welding Intermediate

Oxy-Acetylene Cutting

Safepass

T.I.G. Welding Aluminium Intermediate

T.I.G. Welding Stainless Steel Intermediate

Theory of Welding

2012 FETAC Level 5 – Sport and Recreation

2011 Leaving Certificate

Philip Whitty CV Page 2 of 2

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Motorsport:

I actively participate in the Irish Hillclimb/Sprint Championship as a member of Motorsport Wexford. It's a thrilling experience where I compete in racing events, showcasing my passion and skills in motorsports.

Soccer:

I played soccer for Campile United and had the honour of winning 5 league cup medals. I'm also involved in training some of Campile's underage teams, helping them develop their skills and fostering a love for the sport.

Physical Health and Wellbeing:

Taking care of my physical health and wellbeing is important to me. I enjoy going to the gym regularly, as it allows me to stay fit and maintain a balanced lifestyle.

Technology:

I have been passionate about technology since my teenage years and enjoy exploring applications like Midjourney and Canva. I stay updated on the latest tech trends through YouTube. Lately, I've been familiarising myself with WordPress, although I am still in the learning phase. Technology is my true passion.

REFERENCES

References available on request

Philip Whitty CV Page 3 of 2